Guide to the Edwin Patrick Kilroe Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Edwin Patrick Kilroe Papers,
1776-1959
Kilroe, Edwin P.
ca. 15,000 items (41 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078986
Biographical Note
Edwin Patrick Kilroe (1880-1953) was Assistant District Attorney of New York County and an authority on copyright law.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, original political cartoons, printed and photostatic materials relating to the political and social activities of the Society of Tammany, or Columbian order. Most of the correspondence is concerned with the formation of the Kilroe Tammaniana Collection, Kilroe's collection of books, documents, manuscripts, posters, cartoons, etc. relating to Tammany Hall. Also, letters from various members of the Tammany organization. The manuscripts include typescripts of Kilroe's works such as A Complete Bibliography Of Saint Tammany and Tammany Hall And The Tammany Societies In The United States. In addition there are manuscript and typescript records of various Tammany Societies with particular emphasis on the New York City Society and the New York County Democratic Party organization. Among the cartoons are 22 by John Tinney McCutcheon (1870-1949), over half of which deals with Tammany and New York politics while the remainder concerns national politics with an emphasis on presidential campaigns.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 13 series:
SeriesI: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Reproductions
Series V: Printed Material
Series VI: Woodrow Wilson
Series VII: Photostats
Series VIII: Illustrations and Cartoons
Series IX: Cartoons
Series X: Miscellaneous
Series XI: "Tamaniana" Card Files
Series XII: Scrapbooks
Series XIII: Index of Volumes I-XVIII
Subjects
New York City Society.; Tammany Society, or Columbian Order (N.Y.); Democratic Party (N.Y.); Tammany Hall.; McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949.; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government--To 1898.; United States--Politics and government--19th century.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; New York County Democratic Party.; Presidents--United States--Election.; Cartoons.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-41. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1942 M-42 Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Gift
12/04/91 M-91-12-04 Diary & 24 related items Varela, Marta B. Gift
Related Material
Collections related by provenance: Additional books, manuscripts, and printed ephemera such as newspaper clippings, political memorabilia and campaign literature are in the Kilroe Collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
- SeriesI: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
  - Allen, Stephen To Benjamin F. Thompson, New York, 19 April 1809, (2 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Allen, Stephen To Benjamin F. Thompson, New York, 19 April 1809, (2 page a.l.s. (photocopy; reader must use)) (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Alexander Diary Entry, n.p., 26 Jan 1799, (1 page ms. (copy in hand of A.J. Wall)) (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Frances Smiley (Mrs. Arthur J.) Diary, v.p., 1919, (1 vol.) (Box 1)
    [With t.ms. transcript of diary & research notes of Marta B. Varela on the Baldwin family & Arthur J. Baldwin who was the attorney of Charles F. Muphy, head of Tammany Hall, 1902-1924, 24 items.]
  - Beckner, S.W.E. To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, Oct 1895, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brady, William V. To Elijah F. Purdy, New York, 7 Jan 1848, (2 pages ms.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Crolius, Clarkson To Benjamin F. Thompson, New York, 10 April 1811, (3 pages a.l.s. (photocopy; reader must use)) (Box 1)
  - Devlin, Daniel To Fernando Wood, New York, 28 Dec 1859, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Gaynor, William J. To Edwin P. Kilroe, New York, 18 April 1912, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Goetz, Wolfgang To Hugh Grant, New York, 7 Dec 1892, (6 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grant, Hugh To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, 6 Nov 1890, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grant, Hugh To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, 14 Nov 1890, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grant, Hugh To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, 12 Oct 1891, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - [Guernsey, Richard] To Richard Guernsey, [New York], n.d., (1 page a.l.) (Box 1)
  - Hewitt, Abram S. To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, 22 Dec 1897, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Jefferson, Thomas To Tammany Society of the City of Washington, n.p., 14 Dec 1807, (1 page a.l.s. (photostat)) (Box 1)
  - Kaufman, Louis G. To [Edwin P. Kilroe], New York, 15 March 1919, (1 page t.l.s. (mimeographed, with rubber stamp signature)) (Box 1)
  - McCarthy, William H. To Major Wolgang Goetz, [New York], [22 Oct 1895], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Mittnacht, Jake To Wolfgang Goetz, Albany, 28 Mar 1894, (1 page a.l.s. (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Mooney, William, John P. Roome & Lawrence Myer To Jonas Hawkins, Benjamin F. Thompson & Charles H. Havens, New York, 27 Feb 1810, (2 pages a.l.s. (in Mooney's hand; signed by Roome & Myer; photocopy; Reader must use)) (Box 1)
  - Nast, Mrs. Thomas To Julia [Nast], n.p., 4 Sept [1892], (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - O'Conor, Charles To P. Guernsey, [New York?], 24 July 1875, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - O'Conor, Charles To P. Guernsey, [New York?], 4 Aug 1875, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Parsons, Jacob Cox To James M. Gardiner, New York, 23 Jan 1893, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Parsons, Jacob Cox To James M. Gardiner, New York, 29 Nov 1893, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Phelan, J.J. To William H. Murtha, New York, 23 Oct 1888, (1 page a.l.s. (with envelope)) (Box 1)
  - Potts, E. Styles To Wolfgang Goetz, New York, 27 Oct 1899, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Smith, Alfred Emmanuel To Edward Swann, Albany, 8 Oct 1919, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Smith, Thomas F. To Richard Croker, New York, 14 Oct 1914, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tweed, William Marcy To Frank B. Tinelli, New York, 12 Jan 1871, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Walker, James J. To John Curray, New York, 6 Oct 1932, (3 pages telegram) (Box 1)
  - Wall, A.J. To Edwin Kilroe, New York, 24 April 1919, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [For the above See: Anderson, Alexander. Diary Entry, 26 Jan 1799.]
  - Whalen, Grover A. To Edwin P. Kilroe, New York, Jan-March 1919, (2 t.l.s., 3 p.l.s. (rubber stamp signature)) (Box 1)
    [Relating to the Mayor's Committee of Welcome to Home-Coming Troops]
  - [Whalen], Grover To Edwin P. Kilroe, n.p., [August 1941], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Woodrow To Edwin P. Kilroe, [Trenton], NJ, 27 Feb 1911, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Wood, Fernando To [?], New York, Oct 1878, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - A - B (Box 2)
  - Brylowski (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1918 - 1919 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1921 - 1923 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1925 - 1927 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1928 - 1929 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1930 - 1932 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1933 - 1934 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1935 - 1937 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1938 - 1941 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1942 - 1943 (Box 2)
  - C - H (Box 2)
  - Heller (Box 2)
  - Hines Invitations & Misc. (A - B) (Box 2)
  - Hines Invitations & Misc. (C - E) (Box 2)
  - Hines Invitations & Misc. (F - K) (Box 2)
  - Hines Invitations & Misc. (L - O) (Box 2)
  - Hines Invitations & Misc. (P - Z) (Box 2)
  - Kilroe Campaign, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Kilroe Campaign, 1914 - 1942 (Box 2)
  - MacDonald Material Relating to Book Plates (A - M) (Box 2)
  - MacDonald Material Relating to Book Plates (MacDonald) (Box 2)
  - MacDonald Material Relating to Book Plates (N - Z) (Box 2)
  - MacDonald Book Plate Specimens (Box 2)
  - J - P (Box 2)
  - Prince - R (Box 2)
  - Ray (Box 2)
  - S - Z (Box 2)
  - Volume 1, 1907-1913 (Box 3)
  - Volume 2, 1907-1913 (Box 3)
  - Volume 3, 1907-1913 (Box 3)
  - Volume 4, 1907-1913 (Box 4)
  - Volume 5, 1907-1913 (Box 4)
  - Volume 6, 1907-1913 (Box 4)
  - Volume 7, July 1913-Sept 1915 (Box 5)
  - Volume 8, July 1913-Sept 1915 (Box 5)
  - Volume 9, July 1913-Sept 1915 (Box 6)
  - Volume 10, Nov 1915-Feb 1917 (Box 6)
  - Volume 11, Nov 1915-Feb 1917 (Box 7)
  - Volume 12, Nov 1915-Feb 1917 (Box 7)
  - Volume 13, Jan 1917-Jan 1918 (Box 8)
  - Volume 14, Jan 1918-Oct 1924 (Box 9)
  - Volume 15, Oct 1924-Aug 1928 (Box 10)
  - Volume 16, Aug 1928-Dec 1932 (Box 10)
  - Volume 17, 1910-1936 (Box 11)
  - Volume 18, 1937-1939 (Box 11)
  - , 1940-1944 (Box 12)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Ames, H.V. & L.S. Shimmel Report on Public Archive of Pennsylvania (Box 13)
  - Bernd, Aaron Blum Democratic Organization in the 19th Association District (Box 13)
  - Buck, William J. Tammany (Box 13)
  - Boston Democratic Reading Room Annual Subscription, 1847 (Box 13)
  - Johnson, George W. John Pintard (Box 13)
  - Johnson, John Barent Extracts from Diary of (Box 13)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick American or Tammany Museum - notes (Box 13)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick American or Tammany Museum - lecture (Box 13)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick American or Tammany Museum - related papers (Box 13)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Bibliography Relating to Political Development of New York (Box 13)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Bibliography of Tammany Hall (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Biographical Information (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Catalogue of Tammany Collection (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Early History of Tammany Society (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick History of Tammany Society (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick History of Tammany Hall - Outlines (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Life and Legends of St. Tammany (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick St. Tammany and Origins of Society (Box 14)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Legend of St. Tammany (carbon copies now. 3 & 4) (Box 15)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Legend of St. Tammany - copy 5 pt. 1 (Box 16)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Legend of St. Tammany - copy 5 pt. 2, misc. papers (Box 17)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick New York Democratic Club - History (Box 18)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Origin of Tammany Societies in U.S. (Box 18)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Pennsylvania State Bar Admission (Box 18)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Progress of Our Society (Box 18)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick St. Tammany - Ph.D. Dissertation (Box 18)
  - Kilroe, Edwin Patrick Tammany: A Patriotic History - notes & drafts (Box 19)
  - Kilroe Collection of Tammaniana Inventory, 1916 (Box 20)
  - Kilroe Collection of Tammaniana Enumeration of Items 1000-1238 (Box 20)
  - Kilroe Collection of Tammaniana 'Prefaces,' 'Remarks,' etc. (Box 20)
  - Liberty Cap Notes from New International Encyclopedia (Box 20)
  - Margaret, Mother Mary William Bourke Cockran, Orator (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Charles F. Tammany Society - Summary, History (Box 20)
  - Mooney, William (1755 - 1831) Biographical Material (Box 21)
  - Nast, Thomas Relating to Cartoons (Box 22)
  - List of Newspapers & Periodicals (Box 22)
  - New York County, 11th Associational District Rules and Regulations (Box 22)
  - New York County, 9th Associational District Rules and Regulations (Box 22)
  - Norton, Michael Biographical Material, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Rogers, John R. Tradition of Tammany Hero of the Hill (Box 22)
  - Rynders, Isaiah Obituary Notice (Box 22)
  - St. Tammany Lodge no. 83 Extracts from Proceedings (Box 22)
  - Tammany State of (supposed) (Box 22)
  - Tammany Tamenand (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Account of Meeting, 4 July 1855 (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society African Tammany Society - Sage! Sage! Sage! (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Anniversary of, 1795 (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Annual Celebrations, 4 July 1822 (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Annual Celebrations, 1890, 1896-1899, 1902, 1904-1908 (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Bibliography of the Histories of (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Beaver Tribe (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Hand-Book (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society History (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Opera, 1794, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Tammany Society Minutes and Membership Lists (Box 23)
  - Tammany Society New York Times Index, 1860-1873 (Box 24)
  - Tammany Society New York Times Index, 1874-1877 (Box 24)
  - Tammany Society Notes, Excerpts relating to History, (3 folders) (Box 24)
  - Tammany Society Poems (Box 24)
  - Tammany Society Prices of books relating to Society (Box 24)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Grand March, 1794 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Tiger Cotillion, 1836-1840 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Song for Mayor Wood, 1855 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Jeff in Petticoats, 1865 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Naseby's Lament, 1868 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Solid Men, 1870 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Tammany, 1905 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Ireland, 1909 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Tammany on Parade, 1909 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Bull Moose March, 1912 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Teddy Roosevelt, 1912 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Bull Moose Campaign Song (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Toast to Tammany, 1913 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Wilson, 1916 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Man of the Hour, 1916 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Liberty Anthem, 1918 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Voting for Al, 1924 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Row, with Roosevelt, 1932 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Up in Central Park (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Sheet Music - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Toasts (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations, 1789-1917 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Remarks by E.P. Kilroe (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Daniels, Joesphus (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Davis, Erwin L., 1922 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Dickstein, Samuel (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Drewry, P.H., 1925 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Garrett, Finis J. (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Gallivan, James A. (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Hawes, Harry B., 1923 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Huddleston, George, 1922 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - McCrystal, E., 1919 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Matthews, Annie, 1920 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Mooney, William, 1817 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Neeley, M.M., 1923 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Pell, Herbert C., 1920 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Rorke, Alexander, 1920 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society Talks or Orations - Walsh, David I., 1921 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society - Ohio Notes, 1810-1811 (Box 25)
  - Tammany Society - Washington Minutes, 1807-1810 (Box 25)
- Series IV: Reproductions
  - Tammany Society Proceedings, July 1810 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Celebration, 4 July 1798 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Celebrations, 1793 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Celebrations, 1795-1796 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Constitution of Sons of St. Tammany, 178? (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Signatures of Tammany, 1683-1892 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Miscellaneous Facsimiles (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Miscellaneous Lists (Box 26)
  - Westervelt, Harmon G. History of Tammany Hall, 1789-183[2] (Box 26)
- Series V: Printed Material
  - Beard, James T. First History of Greater New York (Box 26)
  - Great Know-Nothing Song, (1 Broadside) (Box 26)
  - Loco-Focoism, (1 Broadside) (Box 26)
  - Paddy's Fight with the Know-Nothings, (1 Broadside) (Box 26)
  - Roman Catholics to the Front, (1 Broadside) (Box 26)
  - Simple Truth -...Franklin Roosevelt, (1 Broadside) (Box 26)
  - Book Prospectuses (Box 26)
  - Griffin, Appleton P.C. Bibliography on Constitution, 1903 (Box 26)
  - Jersey City Free Library Bibliography on Politics, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Kilroe, E.P. Tammaniana - Prosectuses (Box 26)
  - Law Firms Cards, 1924-1939 (Box 26)
  - Lincoln, Abraham Gettysburg Address, (1 facsimile) (Box 26)
  - National Democratic Club Obituaries, 1928-1929 (Box 26)
  - National Democratic Club Menu - Tammany Hall Dinner (Box 26)
  - New York Civic League (Box 26)
  - Sons of the Revolution 9th Annual Flag Day, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Brookhaen, Nassau, 1910 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Forms (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Extract of Jefferson Inauguaral Address (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Invitation of 40th Anniversary of 1814 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Meeting, 1773 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Obituary Notices, 1913-1937 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Museum Advertisements (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Programme, 1810 (Box 26)
  - Tammany Society Miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Victory Liberty Loan Drive, 1919 (Box 26)
- Series VI: Woodrow Wilson
  - 'Wilson' - Motion Picture, ( Captions) (Box 27)
  - 'Wilson' - Motion Picture, ( Dialogue from Film) (Box 27)
  - 'Wilson' - Motion Picture, ( Programme) (Box 27)
  - 'Wilson' - Motion Picture, ( Script) (Box 27)
  - 'Wilson' - Motion Picture, ( Stills) (Box 27)
  - Commemorative Medallion (Box 27)
- Series VII: Photostats
  - American Museum, 1780-1800 (Box 28)
  - American Museum, 1800-1850 (Box 28)
  - American Museum, 1915 (Box 28)
  - American Museum Printed Material (Box 28)
  - Letters (Box 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1750-1800 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1800-1825 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1825-1900 (Box 28)
  - Tammany Society News Clippings, 1780-1800 (Box 29)
  - Tammany Society News Clippings, 1800-1825 (Box 29)
  - Tammany Society News Clippings, 1825-1900 (Box 29)
- Series VIII: Illustrations and Cartoons
  - Illustrations & Cartoons (Box 29)
- Series IX: Cartoons
  - (Box 29)
- Series X: Miscellaneous
  - (Box 29)
  - Printed Copies of Tammany Hall Rules and Regulations, 1902-1931 (Box 30)
  - Democratic Campaign Textbooks, 1920, 1924, 1928 (Box 30)
  - Two-part Parchment and Leather Scroll, Memorial of A. Schell, 28 March 1928 (Box 30)
  - Photostat of Deed: Tammany Hall Property 145 E. 14 St. (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Property Papers, 1928 (Box 30)
  - Tammany Hall Convention Badges, NY County, 1926 (Box 31)
  - Account Book (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Book of State Platforms, 1905-1926 (Box 41)
  - Minutes of Organizational Metting of Democratic County Committee of New York, 22 Sept. 1959 (Box 41)
  - Minutes of the Tammany Society, 1895-1916 (Box 42)
- Series XI: "Tamaniana" Card Files
  - (I) A-N (Box 32)
  - (II) O-Z (Box 32)
  - (I) A-N (Box 33)
  - (II) O-Z (Box 33)
  - (I) A-J (Box 34)
  - (II) K-S (Box 34)
  - (I) T-Z (Box 35)
  - (II) Index to periodical and newspaper articles (Box 35)
- Series XII: Scrapbooks
  - 1921-1927 (Box 36)
  - 1927-1930 (Box 36)
  - 1930-1933 (Box 37)
  - 1934-1939 (Box 37)
  - 1930 (Box 38)
  - 1931 (Box 38)
  - 1939-1943 (Box 39)
  - 1948-1954 (Box 40)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 40)
  - 1959 (Box 40)
- Series XIII: Index of Volumes I-XVIII
  - Abbatt, William Pages 562 | 510 | 536 | 638 | 702 | 762
  - Abraham, J. Pages 522 | 525 | 574 | 593 | 611 | 615 | 620 | 624 | 625 | 636 | 637 | 638 | 673 | 690 | 697 | 698 | 705 | 726 | 728 | 762 | 768 | 776
  - Abraham's Bookshop Page 898
  - Academy of Political Science Page 908
  - Ackerly, O.B. Page 1
  - Ackerson, Charles J. Page 670
  - Adams, Richard C. Pages 2 | 5
  - Adamson, W.C. Page 728
  - Adjutant-General (Albany) Page 523
  - Adjutant-General (New York) In file No. 1507
  - Agriculture, U.S. Department of Page 5a
  - Alabama Historical Society Page 6
  - Albany Institute of and Historical Society Pages 7 | 8
  - Aldine Book Co. Pages 523 | 636 | 722
  - Allen, A.T. Page 577
  - Alsace-Lorraine Memorial Album Page 853
  - Alumni Council of Columbia University Pages 542 | 761
  - American Antiquarian Society Pages 9 | 26 | 524 | 536 | 590 | 593 | 636 | 638 | 642 | 643 | 656 | 660 | 686 | 697b | 729 | 730 | 738 | 759 | 773 | 783 | 796 | 815 | 853 | 858 | 899
  - American Art Association Pages 523 | 525 | 690 | 762
  - American Embassy (London) Page 586
  - American Historical Review Pages 27 | 524 | 593
  - American Historical Society Page 847
  - American-Irish Historical Society Pages 745 | 854 | 878 | 898 | 907
  - American-Irish Historical Society In file No. 1507
  - American Magazine Page 658
  - American Museum of Natural History Pages 28 | 523 | 598 | 660 | 697d | 740
  - American News Co. Page 524
  - American Photogravure Co. Pages 637 | 698
  - American Press Co. Pages 21a | 29-30
  - American Ribbon & Carbon Co. Page 806
  - American Scenic and Historical Society Pages 657 | 684
  - American (Sunday) Pages 525 | 580
  - American Vigilance Association Page 525
  - Anderson Auction Co. Pages 31 | 523 | 524 | 525 | 562 | 621 | 624 | 625 | 637
  - Anderson, E.H. Pages 776 | 784 | 666 | 668 | 759
  - Anderson Galleries Pages 698 | 702 | 708 | 762 | 806 | 827
  - Anderson, Joe Pages 813 | 827 | 847 | 898
  - Andrews, George Page 603
  - Andrews, Roy Chapman Page 523
  - Anger, John T. Page 30a
  - Antin, Benjamin Page 827
  - Appleton, L. & Co. Pages 637 | 698
  - Appleton, Robert Page 827
  - Appleton, Robert In file No. 1155
  - Arabal Mfg. Co. Pages 806 | 811 | 853 | 933
  - Armstrong, Perry M. Page 637
  - Aronoff, E. Joseph Page 576
  - "Artist" Page 30a
  - Arth, Charles M. Page 552
  - Ashely, Fred D. Pages 597 | 614
  - Ashurst, Henry F. Page 796
  - Ashurst, Henry F. In file No. 1217
  - Atkinson, C.R. Pages 523 | 524 | 525
  - Atkinson, C.R. Page 854
  - Austin, Katherine Pages 523 | 524 | 525 | 562 | 611 | 660 | 697
  - Authors' League of America, Inc. Page 525
  - Axtell, Silas B. Pages 728 | 776
  - Avery, C.L. Page 576
  - Ayres, Stephen B. Page 523
  - Badger, Richard G. Pages 855 | 898
  - Badger, Richard G. In file No. 1155
  - Baker, Gray Hettie Page 827
  - Baker's Great Book Shop Pages 30a | 32 | 526 | 618
  - Baker & Taylor Page 827
  - Balta, Dr. Page 583
  - Bar Association Page 528
  - Barberito, F.A. Page 33
  - Barnard, Eunice Fuller Pages 813 | 827
  - Barnes, Jennie L. Page 531
  - Barr, O.J. Page 15
  - Barrett, N.C. Page 734
  - Bartels, Joseph Page 828
  - Bates, G.F. Page 381
  - Bates, Louis P. Pages 533 | 637 | 639 | 640 | 698
  - Baxter, William J. Page 813
  - Beadle, Philander B. Page 796
  - Beam, William B. Pages 637 | 673
  - Beard, Charles Pages 43a | 77-88 | 528 | 529 | 533 | 547 | 640 | 774 | 793
  - Bennett, Whitman Pages 899 | 900
  - Bennett, Whitman In file No. 1155
  - Bennett, William M. Pages 637 | 673
  - Beseler LanternSlide Co. Pages 827 | 853
  - Beseler Oxygen Co. Page 793
  - Beyer, George J. Pages 34-43a | 527 | 528 | 632 | 615 | 642 | 643
  - Bibliophile Society Pages 687 | 793
  - Bieber, Albert A. Pages 528 | 531 | 623 | 730 | 768 | 789 | 812 | 857 | 901 | 931
  - Bieber, Mrs. Albert A. Pages 773 | 796
  - Bigelow, Frank Pages 610 | 760
  - Binkard, Robert S. Pages 640 | 723
  - Bishop, Joseph Bucklin Pages 642 | 643
  - Bishop, William W. Pages 44 | 46 | 264d
  - Bishopric of New York Chancery Office Page 652
  - Black, Walter J. Co. Page 827
  - Black William Harmon Page 861
  - Blaufox, Lillian Page 813 | 828
  - Bliss P & H Pages 855 | 898 | 903 | 924 | 926 | 936
  - Bloch, Maurice Pages 813 | 827
  - Blumenthal Charles and/or Emanuel Pages 44-45a | 861
  - Board of Elections Page 826
  - Bobbs-Merrill Co. Pages 531 | 628
  - Bobbs-Merrill Co. In file No. 1155
  - Bohan, Owen W. Page 827
  - Bolles, John A. Page 901
  - Bolton, Reginald P. Pages 46 | 528
  - Book-Buyer Page 47
  - Bookwaller, Ball-Greathouse Printing Company Page 863
  - Boston Public Library Pages 569 | 608 | 638 | 643